SARA PEARCE

Web Developer 312-513-8577 sarapearce3.14@gmail.com https://github.com/sarapearce

Product-focused developer building with React, Python and PHP. http://sarapearce.net

Summary

I've had several wins during my time as a startup web developer. Under my business leadership at Left Turn Only, I expanded the development team from one to three, and produced 2x revenue growth in the first year. My transformation of our internal development pipelines and production workflows into a unified design process re-enforced with templated spreadsheets and support wikis has accelerated timelines and improved our overall design sensibilities in service of client satisfaction. Productive under stress, and regularly interfacing with notable/sensitive clients on high-stakes projects, I am a versatile technical manager.

Skills

PROFICIENT

- •Python [Flask, Django] [2]
- React [Redux, Jest, Enzyme] [2]
- PHP [Wordpress, Laravel, PHPUnit] [4]
- HTML/HTML5 [9]
- CSS [3]
- Docker [2]
- Analytics [5]
- Agile/Scrum Workflows [2]

EMERGING

- Behavior Driven Design [1]
- SEM [1]
- UX/UI Design [2]

NEW

- Unity [1]
- VR Modeling [1]
- R data science [1]
- Chatbots [1]

Notables

Sept 2018 2nd place

Expero Machine Learning Hackathon

Oct 2018 3rd place

Daimler Product Hackathon \$2500 Prize

Nov 2018 2nd place

Austin DevWeek Hackathon

Keywords

React, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, jQuery, Javascript, MooTools, Python, Flask, Django, PHP, Zend, Wordpress, Woocommerce, PHPUnit, HTML5, LaTeX, MathML, HTML5 Canvas, CSS, Bootstrap, CSS Grid, Flexbox, Pixel, CLI, Terminal, Docker, Git, Linux, Mac OS, MySql, PostGres, AWS, Google Cloud Platform GCP, SCSS, Grunt, Yarn, Webpack, leadership, team player, responsive design, mobile-first design, UX, design thinking, product design, Software Development Life Cycle SDLC, Agile, Scrum

Career Highlights

Left Turn Only: Lead Developer Austin, TX

March 2016-Present

As a technical lead at Left Turn Only, I actualized business requirements internally and for clients. Since joining LTO, the web development department contributes to over 60% of revenue, and is doubling its revenue every 2 quarters. I also initiated an R&D department to build a 5 year plan of sustainability for the business.

XTech Staffing: Programmer Austin, TX

July-Oct 2017

At XTech, the marketing outreach increased 3x from my projects, while the operations were streamlined by migrating to a new system. I expanded the website for new AdWord campaigns generating a total of 20 new pages, including 3rd party integrations requiring custom Wordpress plugins. I built 25+ business analytics dashboards and graphs for a new CRM/ATS full pipeline business system; as well as trained 12 employees on its use.

Querium: Programmer and Math Specialist Austin, TX

April 2016-July 2017

A resident expert in Mathematics and Curriculum, I was responsible for verifying the accuracy and completeness of the AI Virtual Math tutor. I redesigned the Git Flow for the AI Engineering team, supported and contributed to the automated testing suite, wrote rules for the AI in Mathematica and wrote over 200 math questions for AI testing.

Social Solutions: Software Engineer 1 Austin, TX

June 2014-Dec 2015

As a Software Engineer, I was responsible for at least 1 new feature per release cycle following the SDLC. I also supported QA and Product departments with documentation and additional testing. I worked daily in a MVC design pattern using RESTful deployment. I contributed 8 new features to the product and fixed over 100 major and minor issues in the codebase.

Education

University of Minnesota: BA in Mathematics University of Minnesota: M.Ed in Mathematics